Daniel Felix

Senior PHP Laravel/Vue Developer | LAMP Stack

Maitama 900271 felixdaniel2056@gmail.com +234 810 384 2315

Throughout my 6-year-plus career as a software developer, I have focused on developing scalable and well-documented codes. I enjoy working collaboratively but can also run projects independently. Excited about the prospects of joining a product-driven company.

As a dedicated problem-solver, I display expert skills in backend development using PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter, Python, React, Vue, and supporting languages/libraries/frameworks that solve real-world problems through code.

Through my time freelancing at Upwork and earning the Top Rated rank, I have gained further handson experience in industry-standard development.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

Senior Software Engineer/Team Lead

Portuit Corporation - Delaware, OH February 2021 to Present

- Built and maintained the application that scaled to 100k daily users, communicating with crossfunctional team regarding product and design
- Focused on backend development using Laravel and Codeigniter.
- Oversaw a team of 4-6 members to write scalable codes that increase user conversions by 30% in 2022.
- Utilized excellent creativity and logical thought processes to identify software problems and resolve them.
- Responsible for 100% of engineering, testing, implementation, and maintenance of both codes and codebases.
- Participated in all phases of software development including initial design, prototype development, and production.
- Set and upheld standards for code quality and platform stability.

Top Rated Seller

Upwork - Remote April 2017 to June 2021

- Developed and managed multiple client projects including payment gateways and E-commerce solutions.
- Teamed up with current clients to understand the need for improved functionality, and communicated with engineers and clients to develop enhancements that boosted client satisfaction by 20%.
- Drafted documentation delineating designs and specs for more than 40 client projects.

- Worked with customers or departments on technical issues including software system design and maintenance.
- Partnered with software developers and quality assurance engineers to build and test 4 types of new products.

Software Developer

Webicon Tech - Amsterdam February 2016 to March 2017

- Worked with 5 other junior developers under the supervision of senior full-stack software engineer and manager.
- Received coaching and support from peers and senior full-stack engineer, and gained practical experience in using PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter, and 6 different frontend technologies.
- Highlighted best practices and areas of concern for 3 different teams.
- Wrote clean, robust, testable, reusable, and sustainable codes tailored for embedded systems.
- Translated 20+ wireframes/sketches into working prototypes to refine user interface behaviors.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Evangel University - Nigeria

April 2015 to September 2018

Skills

- JavaScript (4 years)
- Git (3 years)
- Software Development (6 years)
- MySQL (5 years)
- APIs (3 years)
- Laravel (4 years)
- Codeigniter (3 years)
- PHP (5 years)
- HTML5 (6 years)
- CSS (6 years)
- Vue.js (3 years)
- React (2 years)
- jQuery (3 years)
- MVC (4 years)
- AWS (2 years)

Languages

• English - Expert

Google Ads Search Certification

November 2021 to Present

Demonstrate your mastery of building and optimizing Google Search campaigns. Certified users will exhibit the ability to leverage automated solutions like Smart Bidding and Audience Solutions to boost campaign performance for specific marketing objectives.

By earning the Google Ads Search Certification, Google recognizes your ability to:

- Translate a vision for online marketing into a coherent digital marketing strategy
- Develop a Google Search strategy with wider company marketing plans
- Generate a plan to increase leads, sales or web traffic using Google Search
- Develop a plan to reach new and existing customers with Google Search Audiences
- · Ensure your Search marketing plan is aligned with your digital marketing budget

Grow Offline Sales Certification

April 2021 to Present

Validate your proficiency with the Grow Offline Sales marketing objective. Certified users will also demonstrate knowledge of how to create and launch an offline sales strategy.

By earning the Grow Offline Sales Certification, Google recognizes your ability to:

- Create an offline sales strategy that meets your business goals. Use best practices setting yourself up for success.
- Build an offline sales solution for omnichannel and offline-only customers. Create a Performance Max for store goals campaign to promote your in-store products and services.
- Measure the impact of your offline sales strategy.

Assessments

Software developer fit — Proficient

April 2022

Measures the traits that are important for successful software developers

Full results: Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.